瓦雷利亚末日
伊耿一世（AC1-37 在位）
“征服者”
镶嵌红宝石的瓦雷利亚钢王冠
坦格利安家族征服维斯特洛
雷妮丝
伊耿一世的妹妹和妻子
伊尼斯一世（AC37-42 在位）
镶嵌翡翠和珍珠的黄金王冠
杰赫里斯一世（AC48-103 在位）
“和解者”“人瑞王”
镶嵌翡翠和珍珠的黄金王冠
杰赫里斯一世（AC48-103 在位）
“和解者”“人瑞王”
镶嵌翡翠和珍珠的黄金王冠
亚莉珊（AC36-100）
“善良王后”
杰赫里斯一世的妹妹和妻子
贝尔隆（AC57-101）
“勇敢的”“春晓王子”
杰赫里斯一世的儿子和国王之手
阿莱莎（AC60-84）
贝尔隆的妹妹和妻子
戴蒙
“浪荡王子”
贝尔隆的儿子 韦赛里斯一世的弟弟
科利斯·瓦列利安
“海蛇”“潮汛之主”
雷妮丝
“无冕女王”
韦赛里斯一世的堂姐
兰娜尔·瓦列利安（AC100- ）
科利斯和雷妮丝的女儿
奥托·海塔尔
韦赛里斯一世的国王之手
韦赛里斯一世（AC103开始在位至今）
镶嵌翡翠和珍珠的黄金王冠
阿莉森·海塔尔
奥托·海塔尔的女儿
韦赛里斯一世（AC103开始在位至今）
镶嵌翡翠和珍珠的黄金王冠
爱玛·艾林（AC82-112）
韦赛里斯一世的表妹和妻子
奥托·海塔尔
韦赛里斯一世的国王之手
阿莉森·海塔尔
奥托·海塔尔的女儿
雷妮拉
韦赛里斯一世的女儿和王储
改编自 《血与火：坦格利安王朝史》
[美] 乔治·马丁 著
龙 王 家 族
第一季 第二集
浪荡王子 The Rogue Prince
莱安爵士曾是御林铁卫强有力的队长
Ser Ryam was a strong Lord Commander of the Kingsguard.
但已抱恙有时
But he was ill for some time.
但愿他走得安详
He passed in peace, I hope.
韦赛里斯·坦格利安一世
国王
是的 陛下
Yes, Your Grace.
我们发现他在梦中安详地走了
He was found to have passed gently in his sleep.
雷妮拉·坦格利安
韦赛里斯的长女和侍酒
静默姐妹已经在整理他的遗体
His remains are being prepared by the Silent Sisters.
奥托·海塔尔
国王之手
继任的队长是哈罗德爵士
The succeeding Lord Commander, Ser Harrold
希望可以尽快
would like to make haste
梅罗斯
大学士
林曼·毕斯柏里
财政大臣
确认人选补充莱安爵士在御林铁卫中留下的空位
in finding Ser Ryam's replacement on the Kingsguard.
陛下 各位大人
Your Grace. My lords.
御林铁卫很快就能恢复七人满员
The Kingsguard must soon be restored to its full complement of seven.
哈罗德·维斯特林
御林铁卫队长
在首相大人的帮助下
With the help of the Hand
我已经邀请了多位优秀的候选人来到宫廷
I've invited a number of fine candidates to court.
奥托·海塔尔
国王之手
他们全都通过了合理的测试
All have passed fair trials.
我们已经损失了四艘船
Four ships have now been lost.
最新一艘还挂着我的旗帜
The last one was flying my banner.
科利斯·瓦列利安
“海蛇” 海政大臣
石阶列岛已经变成大患
The Stepstones have now grown into a conflagration
诸位却还坐在这里为朝廷上那点事举棋不定
yet you sit here and dither about court business.
科利斯大人 您要是有什么想探讨的……
If you've something to discuss, Lord Corlys...
我就想知道我损失的船和手下应该怎么办
I want to know what is to be done about my ships and my men.
国王会补偿你的船只和人员损失的
The crown will compensate you for your ship and crew
也会对牺牲船员的家属
and make an offering
-进行慰问补偿 -我要的不是补偿
- to the men's families. - I don't want compensation.
我需要武力围剿石阶列岛
I want to seize the Stepstones by force
把这个螃蟹喂食者赶尽杀绝
and burn out this Crabfeeder.
我还没准备好跟自由城邦开战
I am not prepared to start a war with the Free Cities.
这些海盗才不代表自由城邦
These pirates are not the Free Cities.
那你觉得是谁在背后给他们提供船只和钱财？
Who do you think provides them with their ships and tender?
大人 纵观历史
In all of its history, my lord
七大王国从未与自由城邦正式开战
the Seven Kingdoms have never entered open war with the Free Cities.
因为一旦开战
Were that to happen
损失不可计量
the losses would be incalculable.
螃蟹喂食者有什么可惧怕我们的
What reason does the Crabfeeder have to fear us?
国王还允许亲弟弟占据龙石岛
The King's own brother has been allowed to seize Dragonstone
并用他的金袍子队伍加强守备呢
and fortify it with an army of his Gold Cloaks.
戴蒙已盘踞在那里半年之久
Daemon has squatted there for over half a year
国王根本没有任何反对的迹象
without even a protest from the crown.
我得提醒你 科利斯大人
I'll caution you, Lord Corlys.
和国王同桌议事并不代表你与国王平起平坐
A seat at the King's table does not make you his equal.
我已经采取了措施 科利斯
I have acted, Corlys.
我已经向潘托斯和瓦兰提斯派出使节
I've sent envoys to Pentos and Volantis
看是否能达成一些共识
to see if we might find common cause.
船只和人马随时可以出发
Ships and men are at the ready.
我们会解决石阶列岛的 迟早
The Stepstones will be settled in time.
您有龙骑士啊 父王
You have dragonriders, Father.
派我们去吧
Send us.
此事没这么简单 雷妮拉
It isn't that simple, Rhaenyra.
这可以展示力量
It would be a show of force.
至少公主殿下有点想法
At least the Princess has a plan.
我只想说 我们至少可以……
I only meant that we should at least...
可能公主的才能
Perhaps there's some better use
当下可以在别处发挥更好的作用 陛下
for the Princess's talents, Your Grace.
不如你带上公主
Why don't you take the Princess
去看看御林铁卫的候选骑士吧
to see about the new Kingsguard posting
队长大人？
Lord Commander?
是个好主意 陛下
A fine idea, Your Grace.
新的御林铁卫也将护你周全
This knight will protect you as well.
应该由你来选
You should choose.
戴斯蒙·卡伦爵士
Ser Desmond Caron.
一位优秀的骑士 公主
A fine knight, Princess.
上前一步 戴斯蒙爵士
Step forward, Ser Desmond.
罗伊斯·卡伦爵士之子
Son of Ser Royce Caron
戴斯蒙爵士已经证明自己在
Ser Desmond has proved strong and steady
比武赛场的场上场下都能强有力地稳定发挥
in both the tourney lists and without.
在前来君临途径御林的路上
While traveling through the Kingswood on his way to King's Landing
戴斯蒙爵士将一个想偷猎的人绳之以法
Ser Desmond recently brought a would-be poacher to justice.
您应当感谢他的忠诚侍奉 公主
You might thank him for his leal service, Princess.
我们感谢你对国王的忠诚侍奉 爵士
We thank you for your loyal service to the crown, ser.
莱门·梅利斯特爵士
Ser Rymun Mallister.
海疆城莱蒙·梅利斯特伯爵之子
Son of Lord Lymond Mallister of Seagard.
果酒厅团体比武的冠军
Winner of the melee at Cider Hall.
他是二十三名骑士中唯一没被打下马的
He was the last mounted of three-and-twenty knights.
莱门爵士受封时才18岁
Ser Rymun was knighted at eight-and-ten.
这些骑士谁有实战经验？
Do any of these knights have combat experience?
抓偷猎者不算
Beyond capturing poachers.
克里斯顿·科尔爵士
Ser Criston Cole.
黑港伯爵管家的儿子
Son of the steward of the Lord of Blackhaven.
克里斯顿·科尔
欢迎 克里斯顿爵士
Be welcome, Ser Criston.
你见识过风暴地的战斗
You saw combat in the Stormlands.
在多恩边疆地 公主
Dornish marches, Princess.
我作为步兵跟多恩进犯者打了一年
I fought for a year as a foot solider against the Dornish incursions.
阿兰·唐德利恩爵士封我为骑士
Ser Arlan Dondarrion knighted me
当时我们突袭了骨路上的两处瞭望塔
after we razed two of the watchtowers along the Boneway.
我选克里斯顿·科尔爵士
I choose Ser Criston Cole.
我们不要这么快做决定 公主殿下
Let's not be too hasty, Princess.
克里斯顿爵士无疑是出色的战士
There's no doubt Ser Criston is a fine warrior
但克雷赫和梅利斯特这些家族
but houses such as Crakehall and Mallister
雷妮丝·坦格利安
“无冕女王” 韦赛里斯的堂姐 科利斯的妻子
都是国王重要的盟友
are important allies of the crown.
就比如海疆城 是王国应对铁群岛劫掠威胁
Seagard, for instance, is the realm's prime defense
主要的防守力量
against reavers from the Iron Islands.
他们只是比武会的骑士
Those men are tourney knights.
父王需要一个有实战经验的人来保护
My father should be defended by a man who's known real combat.
不是吗？
Should he not?
当然 公主明智
Of course, Princess.
那就快去安排克里斯顿爵士的就职礼吧
Well, let us plan Ser Criston's investiture then.
瓦雷利亚的首都修建在火山之上
The Valyrian capital was built into a volcano
就像龙石岛
much like Dragonstone.
而龙王 那些地位最高的贵族
And the dragonlords, the highest of the nobility
就栖身于此 在火山的表面
lived here, at the volcanic face
紧贴魔法和力量的源泉
closest to the source of their magic and power.
Anogrion，瓦雷利亚语“庙宇”之意，词源是ānogar，“血”。
这里则是“血庙”
And this was the Anogrion.
血巫在这里精进他们的技艺
Where the bloodmages worked their craft.
阿莉森·海塔尔
奥托之女
您的造物 真是美轮美奂
It is truly wondrous, what you've built.
过奖
Oh, no.
我不过是查阅了历史 做了点规划
I only pore over the histories and provide the plans.
石匠们才是它真正的建造者
The stonemasons built the structures.
您认为维斯特洛能够成为下一个瓦雷利亚么 陛下？
Do you believe that Westeros can be another Valyria, Your Grace?
看情况
That depends
得看你到底说的是自由堡垒的全盛时期还是衰败年代
whether you speak of the Freehold at its height or at its fall.
上千头龙
Over a thousand dragons,
还有一支足以横跨世界海洋的庞大舰队
a navy large enough to span the seas of the world.
瓦雷利亚的旧日荣光必然已经无法重现于世
The glory of Old Valyria will never be seen again.
七层地狱啊
Seven Hells.
说说吧 雷妮拉状态如何
Tell me, how is Rhaenyra?
您指什么？
What do you mean?
这些日子 她始终不愿意跟我多说一句话
Well, these days, she doesn't say more than a few words to me.
我感觉她现在可能很难开口
I think she might find it difficult
谈论私事
to discuss personal matters.
给她点时间吧
It will take time.
我母亲去世时 我也低迷了一段时间
It did when I lost mine own mother.
我真希望她能来找我聊聊
I wish she would approach me.
如果您去找她呢？
What if you went to her?
有时候我宁愿直面“黑死神”
There are times when I would rather face the Black Dread himself
也不愿面对我那十五岁的女儿
than mine own daughter of fifteen.
我认为如果您主动点的话 她会向您敞开心扉的
I think she would open herself to you if invited.
您有着那么平易近人的一面 陛下
You do have such an easy way about you, Your Grace.
你没有和雷妮拉提起过我们的谈话吧？
You do not mention our talks to Rhaenyra, do you?
我只是……
I just...
我怕她误会
I fear that she wouldn't understand them.
我没有提过 陛下
No, Your Grace.
我的母亲才去世刚半年
It's only been half a year since my mother died
他们就试图让父亲再娶
and already they tried to marry my father off
然后好换掉我这个继承人
and replace me as heir.
我了解这些人
I know those men
也知道在我被打发走后
and how they plot in their secret councils
他们是怎么在御前会议中密谋的
when I've been sent away.
你无法为国王和大臣们的事务操心 雷妮拉
You cannot worry at the matters of lords and kings, Rhaenyra.
假如你父亲真的再娶了呢？
What if your father were to remarry?
你的父亲很爱你
Your father loves you.
他选择了你作为继承人
He chose you for his heir.
他才不是选择了我 他只是撇开了戴蒙
He didn't choose me. He spurned Daemon.
陪我一起跪下吧
Kneel with me.
我发现这样可以感受到母亲与我同在
I find this is a way to be with my mother.
在这静谧的圣堂中……
Here in the quiet of the Sept...
我感觉她就在我的身边
I feel close to her.
- 我知道这听上去有点傻 - 我不觉得傻
- I know it sounds foolish. - I don't think it's foolish.
- 真的不觉得 - 那就好
- I don't. - Good.
因为我觉得你也可以试试
Because I thought you might try.
那好
Aye.
就算你不相信我 或许相信一下诸神
If not for me, then perhaps for them.
我该说点什么？
What do I say?
你想说什么都可以
Whatever you wish.
只有你和诸神才会知道
It's only for you and the gods to know.
我希望父亲不再只是把我当成一个小女孩了
I want him to see me as more than his little girl.
我父亲也读不懂女孩子的心思
Mine own father does not know the language of girls either.
当我想和他聊聊的时候
When I wish to talk with him
我知道我必须主动些
I know that I must make the effort.
谢谢你
Thank you.
陛下
Your Grace.
我很高兴我们可以聊一聊
I'm glad we could meet.
我知道今天大家的火气有点大
I know tempers ran hot today
而我想向你保证
and I wanted to assure you
我非常珍视我们家族之间的深厚情谊
how much I value the bond between our houses.
毕竟雷妮丝是我最喜欢的近亲了
Rhaenys is my favorite cousin after all.
我想为我今天
I wish to apologize
在御前会议上的语调道歉 陛下
for the tenor at the small council today, Your Grace.
我的本意并非冒犯您
It was not my intent to make offense.
你的舰队是王国最重要的资产之一 科利斯大人
Your fleet is one of the realm's most important assets, Lord Corlys.
但你必须要明白……
But you must understand...
作为国王 我有义务避免战争
as King, it is my obligation to avoid war
除非战争无法避免
until such time it is unavoidable.
我们都不希望公然开战
None among us desire open war.
但我可以直言相告吗 陛下？
Might I speak plainly, Your Grace?
我向来欢迎
I always welcome
御前会议的大臣们直言进谏
the unfettered thoughts of my council.
我担心我们的敌人现在已经盯上了红堡
I fear that the eyes of our enemies are presently fixed on the Red Keep.
王后去世了
The Queen has passed.
一个女孩被指定为铁王座的继承人
A girl has been named heir to the Iron Throne...
这可是历史上的头一次
the first in its history.
国王的弟弟 被剥夺了继承权后
The King's brother, so disinherited
占据了龙石岛上的坦格利安族堡
has claimed the Targaryen seat on Dragonstone
无人质询
without challenge.
而现在 一股外来势力在我们最重要的航线上
And now, a foreign power has established a colony
建立了殖民地
in our most critical shipping lane.
你为我的统治描绘了一幅充满机遇的的图景 科利斯大人
You paint such an aspirant portrait of my reign, Lord Corlys.
可这是实话 堂弟
It is an honest one, Cousin.
当下 你的王位看上去显得有些脆弱
At the moment, the crown is perceived as being vulnerable.
盲目地进攻石阶列岛
And a blind incursion in the Stepstones
就是证明我们并不脆弱的唯一办法吗？
is the only way to demonstrate that we are not?
想要渡过风暴
To elude a storm
要么径直驶入风暴 要么环绕风暴而行
you can either sail into it or around it.
绝不能静待风暴降临
But you must never await its coming.
你有什么实际行动的建议吗……
Do you have a specific course of action to propose...
大人？
my lord?
联合我们的家族
Join our families.
迎娶我们的女儿 兰娜尔
Wed our daughter, Laena.
把两个幸存的瓦雷利亚大家族联合起来
Unite the two great surviving Valyrian houses.
坦格利安家的龙和瓦列利安家的舰队通过血脉结合在一起
With the Targaryen dragons and the Velaryon fleet bound in blood
您就可以向全天下展示
you can show the realm
王权的统治依然是东升的旭日 而非昔日的荣光
that the crown's strongest days are ahead, not behind.
我必须要承认……
I must admit...
我还没怎么考虑过再婚
I haven't given marriage much thought.
爱玛去世还不到半年
It hasn't even been half a year since Aemma passed.
全境上下都预计您早晚会续弦 陛下
The realm expects you to take a new wife soon or late, Your Grace
续弦将增强您的血脉 诞下更多子嗣
to strengthen your line and produce more heirs.
您找不到比兰娜尔更强的人选了
You could not ask for a stronger match than Laena.
我们很久没怎么说话了……
We haven't spoken much...
自那以后
since.
我很后悔
A regret of mine.
我们应该对彼此敞开心扉
We should be free to speak our minds to one another.
您想说什么都可以
You can say whatever you'd like.
您是国王
You are the King.
我非常爱你的母亲
I loved your mother very much.
我也是
As did I.
哈罗德爵士带来了一院子的比武骑士供我选择
Ser Harrold provided a fine field of tourney knights.
哦？
Oh?
不过在询问的时候
But in questioning them
我发现他们当中只有克里斯顿爵士
I discovered that Ser Criston was the only man among them
拥有真正的战场经验
with true battle experience.
他会成为一个优秀的御林铁卫
He'll make a fine knight of the Kingsguard.
- 今天在御前会议…… - 别放在心上
- Today at small council... - Pay it no mind.
我本以为自己有一些洞见……
I thought I might have had some insight...
你还年轻
You're young.
会学到的
You will learn.
这是保住手指的最好办法了 陛下
This is our best chance to save the digit, Your Grace.
这些蛆会吃掉死肉
The maggots will remove the dead flesh
但愿还能防止腐烂扩散
and hopefully stop the advance of the rot.
早些时候我会见了
I held an audience earlier today
科利斯大人和雷妮丝公主
with Lord Corlys and Princess Rhaenys.
您这样做非常仁慈 陛下
That was most charitable of you, Your Grace.
我相信科利斯大人会心存感激
I'm sure Lord Corlys appreciated the spirit of it.
他向我提议了一桩婚事
He proposed a marriage.
他提议的人选是谁呢 陛下？
To whom, Your Grace?
兰娜尔小姐
The Lady Laena.
此举将合并我们两大家族的实力
To combine the strength of our houses
彰显出我的统治会如东升旭日般日渐强盛……
and demonstrate my reign's strongest days are ahead...
而非只有昔日荣光
not behind.
科利斯大人僭越了 陛下
Lord Corlys has overreached, Your Grace.
此等大事应当在御前会议中讨论
Such matters must be discussed with the small council.
我这不正在和你讨论呢
That is what I'm doing, presently.
亲爱的奥托 你有何建议呢？
So, what is your advice, dear Otto?
兰娜尔小姐
The Lady Laena
还年幼 陛下
is young, Your Grace.
此话没错
Indeed...
然而当年大议会造成的裂痕
but the wounds made by the Great Council
依然挥之不去 陛下
still linger, my King.
迎娶他们的女儿是在弥合裂痕的路上
A match with their daughter would go a long way towards...
迈出一大步
sealing the breach
两个伟大的瓦雷利亚家族的联姻
and uniting the two great Valyrian houses
无疑是向举国上下放出团结的信号
would certainly signal unity throughout the realm
对国外也一样
and beyond.
大学士所言有理
The Grand Maester's reasoning is sound.
我倒担心雷妮拉会怎么想
I do fear what Rhaenyra might think.
这有什么关系呢 陛下？
What does it matter, Your Grace?
她的母亲去世了
Her mother has passed.
她的父亲必须延续王室血脉
Her father must propagate the royal line.
我也深爱过我的妻子
I dearly loved my own lady wife.
她的逝去带来的痛苦依然萦绕我的心头
The pain of her passing still haunts me.
然而我被迫另寻她人
And to be compelled to...
以履行义务
replace her for duty's sake...
您是国王
You are the King
但在这点上我们是相通的
but I do not envy you.
兰娜尔·瓦列利安
科利斯之女
骑着“黑死神”在天空中翱翔是什么感觉？
What was it like flying the Black Dread?
您是贝勒里恩的最后一位骑手
You were Balerion's last rider.
那只是他死前很短暂的一段时光
Only for a short time before he died.
古瓦雷利亚最后的回忆也随他一并逝去
With Balerion died the last memory of Valyria of Old.
可瓦格哈尔还活着
But Vhagar still lives...
在某处
somewhere.
对于龙穴来说 她太大了
Bit too large for the Dragonpit.
有人会说 她对我们的世界来说也太大
Some would say too large for our world.
- 您知道她在哪儿筑巢吗？ - 你说什么？
- Do you know where she nests? - I'm sorry?
您知道瓦格哈尔现在何处吗？
Do you know where Vhagar is now?
啊 龙卫们认为
Ah. The dragonkeepers believe
她在狭海沿岸某处安了家
she made home somewhere on the coast of the Narrow Sea.
香料镇的工人时不时报告能听到她的歌声
The workers at Spicetown report hearing her song at times.
他们说她听上去很悲伤
They say it is a sad thing.
我想就连龙也会感到孤独
I imagine even dragons get lonely.
陛下
Your Grace.
若能像古瓦雷利亚时那样联合我们两家
It would be a great honor
会是莫大的荣耀
to join our houses as they were in Old Valyria.
我能为您诞下许多拥有纯正瓦雷利亚血统的孩子
I would give you many children of pure Valyrian blood
这将巩固王室血脉与全境统治
so that we might strengthen the royal line and the realm.
这是你的父亲教你说的？
Is that what your father told you to say?
你的母亲是怎么跟你说的？
What did your mother tell you?
她说在我十四岁之前 我不会与您圆房
That I wouldn't have to bed you until I turned fourteen.
这让你很困扰 对不对？
It bothers you, does it not?
我的父亲是国王
My father is a king.
续弦添子是他的义务
It is his duty to take a new wife and strengthen his line.
我不想听你来讲授政治
I did not ask for a lesson in politics.
我问你的是 你是否为此困扰
I asked whether this bothers you.
兰娜尔是您的女儿 公主殿下
Laena is your daughter, Princess.
那您是否困扰？
Does it bother you?
当然
Of course it does.
但我明白凡事都有秩序
But I understand the order of things.
我不清楚你是否明白
I'm not sure you do.
如果您想激怒我
If you mean to elicit some anger from me
您做得并不成功 公主殿下
you should know that you're failing, Princess.
恰恰相反
Quite the opposite.
无论是我的女儿 还是其他家族的小姐
Whether it's to my daughter or to someone else's
你父亲迟早会再娶妻
your father will remarry sooner than late.
新王后会诞下新继承人
His new wife will produce new heirs
其中大有可能会有男性
and chances are better than not that one of those will be male.
当王子到了年龄 一旦你父王去世
And when that boy comes of age and your father has passed
天下人会期盼王子继位
the men of the realm will expect him to be heir...
而不是你
not you.
这就是世间万物的秩序
Because that is the order of things.
等我成为女王 我会创造新的秩序
When I'm Queen, I will create a new order.
我多希望那能成真 雷妮拉
How I wish that could be, Rhaenyra.
不过七大王国的人曾有机会
But the men of the realm already had their opportunity
在大议会上任命一位女王
to appoint a ruling queen at the Great Council
但他们拒绝了
and they denied it.
他们拒绝的是你 雷妮丝公主
They denied you, Princess Rhaenys.
“无冕女王”
"The Queen Who Never Was."
但他们屈膝于我 尊称我为铁王座的继承人
But they bent the knee to me and called me heir to the throne.
当你为御前会议斟酒时 也会这样说么？
Do you remind your father's men of that as you carry their cups?
听好这个冷酷的事实
Here is the hard truth
——别人才不会好心告诉你
which no one else has the heart to tell you.
男人们宁愿将王国付之一炬
Men would sooner put the realm to the torch
也不愿看到女人登上铁王座
than see a woman ascend the Iron Throne.
你父王并不傻
And your father is no fool.
御前会议力促我再娶
The small council is urging me to remarry.
看来王国需要新王后
It seems the realm wants for a new queen.
一位贤惠善良的王后会为您的臣民带来安慰
A good and kind queen will give comfort to your subjects.
御前议会是否已经中意哪位小姐了？
Does the small council have a particular lady in mind?
科利斯·瓦列利安伯爵提名他女儿
Lord Corlys Velaryon has offered the hand of his daughter...
兰娜尔小姐
the Lady Laena.
这是个强力人选 陛下
A very strong match, Your Grace.
实话实说 我不怎么了解兰娜尔
I must admit, I don't know Laena very well.
我相信她是一位贤惠善良的小姐
I'm sure that she is good and kind
她会享受您的陪伴 陛下 就像我一样
and that she will enjoy your company as I have, Your Grace.
我带了东西给您
I brought you something.
我让石匠修好了它
I asked the stonemasons to mend it.
这真是
This is...
太好心了 阿莉森
a very kind gesture, Alicent.
太好心了
Very kind.
进来
Come.
陛下 是御前首相
The Hand, Your Grace.
陛下 我已经召集了御前会议成员
Your Grace, I've called the small council
开一个紧急会议
to an emergency session.
为什么？
Why?
我想您最好能直接与会
I think it best you hear it directly.
好吧
Very well.
这件事发生在深夜时分 诸位大人
Atroksio sȳndrorro massitas, āeksīs ñuhis.
在蝠时 窃贼躲过了我们的追捕
Masso Jēdunna. Laodikio īlot upȳdas.
龙蛋怎么会在五十多名龙卫眼皮下被偷走的？
Skorkydoso zaldrīzo drōmon tōmēpsa urneroti rȳ laodikson kōttas?
犯人是戴蒙王子 陛下
Dārilaros Daemon sikio sīdas, Eglivys Aōhys…
- 戴蒙？ - 亲王留下了一封信
- Daemon? - The Prince left a missive
或许可以解释他的动机
which I believe might explain.
戴蒙·坦格利安
"It is the pleasure of Daemon Targaryen...
龙石岛亲王
the Prince of Dragonstone
铁王座合法继承人
and rightful heir to the Iron Throne...
在此宣布 他将依循古瓦雷利亚传统
to announce that he is to take a second wife
迎娶第二位妻子
in the tradition of Old Valyria.
她将冠以龙石岛的梅莎丽亚夫人这一尊称
She is to assume the title Lady Mysaria of Dragonstone.
殿下已怀有孩子
Her Grace is with child
根据坦格利安家族习俗
and is to have a dragon's egg placed in the babe's cradle
新生儿的摇篮中将放置一枚龙蛋
in the custom of House Targaryen."
陛下 戴蒙王子邀请您参加他的婚礼
The Prince has invited you to his wedding, Your Grace.
- 就在两天后 - 诸神保佑
- It is in two days' time. - Gods be good.
梅莎丽亚夫人是谁？
Who is Lady Mysaria?
- 据我们所知 - 是戴蒙的婊子
- We believe... - Daemon's whore.
- 这无异于煽动叛乱 - 我非常赞同 大人
- This is nothing less than sedition. - I strongly agree, sire.
我的弟弟想要激怒我
My brother wishes to provoke me.
回应反倒正中他的下怀
To answer is to give him what he wants.
举国上下都在看着呢 陛下
The realm is watching, Your Grace.
你想让我怎样？
What would you have me do?
把他发配去绝境长城？
Send him to the Wall?
或许我可以把他的脑袋插在长矛上
Perhaps I could put his head on a spike.
戴蒙已经占领了龙石岛
Daemon has seized Dragonstone.
身边围绕着金袍子军队
Has surrounded himself with an army of Gold Cloaks
现在又盗取了危险的武器
and has now stolen a dangerous weapon.
哪颗龙蛋 长老？
Skorior drōmon, Uēpys?
戴蒙拿走了哪颗龙蛋？
Skorior drōmon Daemon lāettas?
梦火的蛋 公主
Drōmon Ēdrurzo īles, Dārilaros.
您为贝尔隆王子的摇篮选的那颗
Dārilaro Baelo mazumbille iderēptā hēnkon luon.
组个小队 奥托
Assemble a detachment, Otto.
我要亲自去龙石岛把戴蒙抓回来
I will go to Dragonstone and drag Daemon back
- 接受审判 - 陛下
- to face justice myself. - Your Grace.
抱歉 陛下 但我不能允许
My apologies, Your Grace, but I cannot allow it.
那太危险了
It's too dangerous.
戴蒙无法无天
Daemon is without limit.
让我去龙石岛吧
Let me go to Dragonstone.
你是整个王宫里最标致的姑娘
You're the most comely girl at court.
为什么要伤害自己呢？
Why do you destroy yourself?
你今晚会去见国王吗？
Will you see the King tonight?
如果您希望的话
If you wish it.
- 日安 克里斯顿爵士 - 小姐
- Good day, Ser Criston. - My Lady.
我召集了二十个您最好的家兵 国王之手大人
I've assembled 20 of your best household guards, my Lord Hand.
哈罗德爵士会和我们一起去
Ser Harrold will also join us.
请照顾好国王之手 克里斯顿爵士
Please look after the Hand, Ser Criston.
戴蒙·坦格利安
“浪荡王子” 韦赛里斯的弟弟
梅莎丽亚
“小梅夫人” 戴蒙的情妇
欢迎来到龙石岛 奥托
Welcome to Dragonstone, Otto.
你在这个岛的占领期到此为止
Your occupation of this island is at an end.
你要交出龙蛋
You're to relinquish the dragon's egg
遣散你的军队
disband your army
驱逐你的婊子……
banish your whore...
然后遵照韦赛里斯国王陛下的命令
and leave Dragonstone by order of His Grace
- 离开龙石岛 - 国王在哪呢？我没看到他
- King Viserys. - Where is the King? I don't see him.
陛下绝不会自降身份来参加这样一个戏子的闹剧
His Grace would never lower himself to entertain such a mummer's farce.
是克里斯宾爵士 对吗
Ser Crispin, wasn't it?
是克里斯顿·科尔爵士 王子
Ser Criston Cole, my Prince.
对 抱歉 我记不住
Yes, apologies. I couldn't recall.
也许王子记得住我把他打下马这事
Perhaps my Prince recalls when I knocked him off his horse.
- 不错 - 这真是场可悲的作秀
- Very good. - This is a truly pathetic show
戴蒙
Daemon.
你就这么迫切地渴望得到国王的关注
Are you so desperate for the King's attention
不惜像一个平凡的扒手那样偷盗？
that you've resorted to skulking about like a common cutpurse?
我只不过是在遵循家族的传统
I'm simply keeping with the traditions of my house
就像我哥给他的继承人做的一样
the same as my brother did for his heir.
这些传统是为王族的嫡生后裔所设
Those traditions are for the trueborn children of royalty.
而不是一个普通婊子的私生子
Not for bastards fathered on a common whore.
梅莎丽亚小姐将会成为我的妻子
Lady Mysaria is to be my wife.
这真是造孽
This is an abomination.
你的每次呼吸都是在玷污你的名字
With every breath, you soil your name
你的家族和你哥哥的统治
your house and your brother's reign.
爱又不分头衔和传统
Our love does not know titles and traditions.
那么你们呢 都城守备队的士兵们？
And what of you, men of the City Watch?
帮助王子叛国吗？
Aiding the Prince in his treason?
国王任命我为他们的指挥官
The King made me their commander.
他们忠诚于我
They are loyal to me.
你是为了这龙蛋来的
You've come for the egg.
它就在这
Here it is.
你疯了吗
Are you mad?
- 你会死的 - 我很乐意 反正你也活不下来
- You'd never survive this. - Well, happily, neither would you.
在此地诉诸暴力就是在向你的国王宣战
To choose violence here is to declare war against your King.
太好了
Wonderful.
就算这会使你未出生的孩子随母亲一道死去？
Even if it ends in the death of your unborn child and its mother?
科拉克休
戴蒙的龙
所有人
All of you.
把该死的兵器收回去
Sheathe the fucking steel.
叙拉克斯
雷妮拉的龙
- 你在这里干什么 公主？ - 阻止流血
- What are you doing here, Princess? - Preventing bloodshed.
克里斯顿爵士 请护卫公主到安全的地方
Ser Criston, please escort the Princess to safety.
小心不要惊动叙拉克斯 大人们
Take care not to startle Syrax, my lords.
她很护我的
She's rather protective of me.
我父亲立我为龙石岛公主
Kepa ñuha yne Zaldrīzdōro Dārilaroso brōstas.
你住到我的城堡里了 叔叔
Kesy uglaesā luon sombāzmion ñuhon issa, kepus.
等你成年了才是你的
Iā sīlāvose iōrō, daor.
你惹怒了你的国王
Vēdroso dāri aōhi iqīdā.
我看不出缘由
Indirarion urnion daor.
这是个值得庆贺的日子 我要结婚了
Tubī manaeri. Nyke dīnilaks.
你已经有妻子了
Ābrazȳri sīr emā.
不是我选的人
Derēptan lī, daor.
所以你就要偷走我弟弟的龙蛋？
Se kejo syt ñuho valonqro drōmon laodigon aō bēviltas?
你出生的时候和一条龙共享了摇篮
Bībot zaldrīzome mazumbillo vulē.
我想要我的孩子得到同样待遇
Konir ñuho rūho syt jaelan.
你要有孩子了？
Sikilāt?
总有一天会有的
Māzīlarē tubī.
我就在这里 叔叔
I'm right here, Uncle.
你愤怒的对象
The object of your ire.
你被剥夺继承权的原因
The reason that you were disinherited.
如果你想恢复继承人的身份 你需要杀了我
If you wish to be restored as heir, you'll need to kill me.
动手吧
So do it.
把这些麻烦都解决了
And be done with all this bother.
你宣布我们要结婚？
You announced that we were to be wed?
明天就结
On the morrow.
还说我怀了孩子
And that I was with child.
你的孩子
Your child.
也许等我们结婚了 这事就能成真了
Well, perhaps when we are wed, we can make that true.
我很早以前就确保了 我绝不会为生产所迫
I ensured long ago that I would never be threatened by childbirth.
太好了 孩子有时候是那么烦人
Good. Children can be such irritating creatures.
你发誓要保护我的 戴蒙
You swore to protect me, Daemon.
龙石岛非常安全
Dragonstone is quite secure.
直到国王决定收回他祖传的族堡
Until the King decides to reclaim his ancestral seat.
他的士兵也许不会把王子的脑袋插在长矛上
His men might not put the Prince's head on a spike
但他们对王子宣称要与之结婚生子的
but what would they do with the common whore
一个普通的婊子又会怎样呢？
he claims he's taken to wife and made with child?
没有人会伤害你的
No one will harm you.
我已经无数次被作为财产贩卖了 都懒得数了
I have been sold as property more times than I care to count
最开始是在一个我都不记得的家乡
beginning in a homeland I can no longer recall.
我的大部分人生都是在恐惧中度过的
Most of my years have been spent living in terror.
你和我在一起很安全 我保证
You're safe with me, I swear it.
你是坦格利安家族的人
You are Targaryen.
你大可以和国王玩你愚蠢的游戏
You can afford to play your stupid games with the King
但我不行
but I cannot.
我来服侍你不是为了金子或权力
I didn't come into your service wanting gold or power
或是地位
or station.
- 我来到你身边是想要解放 - 解放？
- I came to you to be liberated. - Liberated?
从谁手里解放？
From what?
恐惧
Fear.
莱昂诺·斯壮
法务大臣
不必多礼 请坐 莱昂诺伯爵
No, please, Lord Lyonel.
我希望得到无所顾忌的意见
I have come looking for an unencumbered opinion.
我一直致力于此 陛下
That's all I would ever give, Your Grace.
自从我的名字
Ever since my name was read
被大议会的博士念出
by the archmaesters at the Great Council
科利斯·瓦列利安嫉妒的眼神就一直盯着我
I have felt Corlys Velaryon's envious gaze staring at me
都越过了黑水湾
from across the Blackwater.
您坐在王国的最高位置上 陛下
You sit upon the highest seat in the realm, Your Grace.
骄傲的人们不喜欢仰头看人
Proud men don't like having to look up.
兰娜尔·瓦列利安
Laena Velaryon.
科利斯爵士是您的海政大臣
Lord Corlys is your Master of Ships
而她是王国里最富裕家族的长女
and she is the eldest daughter of the wealthiest house in the realm.
她毫无疑问来自瓦雷利亚世族
She comes from unimpeachable Valyrian stock
并且还有坦格利安血统
and she has Targaryen blood.
- 有何不可呢？ - 她十二岁
- What's to mislike? - She is twelve.
她会长大的
She will mature.
我从未要求再婚
I never asked to remarry.
作为国王 您拥有一切
As King, you have a claim on all things.
甚至是那些您不想要的
Even those you don't want.
婚姻这项义务您无法逃避太久
Marriage is not an obligation you can put off for long.
如果我拒绝科利斯爵士的提议呢？
What if I was to reject Lord Corlys's proposal?
他很可能不会坦然接受
He would not be like to take it well.
我担心除了一条通往铁王座的直线之外 没有什么能让他满意
I fear nothing short of a direct line to the Iron Throne would satisfy him.
你还需要考虑一下
You should also consider
我们现在在石阶列岛的情况
that we find ourselves on the precipice of war
正处于开战的边缘
in the Stepstones.
而海蛇掌握了全国将近一半的舰队
And the Sea Snake holds claim to nearly half the realm's ships.
如果国家有需要 他怎敢拒绝
He would not dare withhold them in the face of the realm's need.
- 谁敢威胁我？ - 没人敢 陛下
- Who is he to hector me? - No one, Your Grace.
但潮头岛那边做盟友要好过做敌人
But Driftmark makes for a better ally than it does an enemy.
海蛇已经算计好了
The Sea Snake has made a calculated reach.
对他这个地位的人来讲 这才算公平
A fair play for a man of his position.
如果您真心想听我的诚挚意见……
If you truly want my unencumbered opinion...
说吧
I do.
您应该迎娶兰娜尔·瓦列利安 陛下
You should wed Laena Velaryon, Your Grace.
满足科利斯大人的要求 让他稳稳站在你这边
Sate Lord Corlys and fix him at your side
永远结为盟友
permanently, as an ally.
陛下
Your Grace.
公主从龙石岛回来了
The Princess has returned from Dragonstone.
龙石岛？
Dragonstone?
陛下
Your Grace.
你违背我的命令
You disobeyed me.
你一字不提就离开君临
You fled King's Landing without a word
而且没有国王的许可就擅自行动
and you acted without the crown's leave.
你是我唯一的继承人
You are my only heir.
你有可能遇害
You could've been killed.
我能坐下吗？
May I sit?
你去了龙石岛
You went to Dragonstone.
还取回了龙蛋 没流一滴血
And retrieved the egg without bloodshed.
我不确定奥托爵士能完成如此壮举
A feat I'm not sure Ser Otto could've accomplished alone.
是的 的确……
Yes, well...
有时候我都忘记了你们究竟有多像
I sometimes forget how alike you both were.
你母亲的离去 是我永远无法愈合的伤口
Your mother's absence is a wound that will never heal.
没有她
Without her
红堡失去了温暖
the Red Keep has lost a warmth
我敢说它永远都无法恢复如初了
that I dare say it will never recover.
我很高兴听到你这么说
It pleases me to hear you say this.
知道我并不是一个人在悲伤
To know that I'm not alone in my grief.
我真希望她走以后
I wish I had known better...
我能知道该对你说些什么
what to say to you in the aftermath.
我好不容易才意识到
I struggled to realize
我的女儿这么快就长成了一个女人
that my daughter had so quickly become a woman grown.
但我知道
But I know
她懂我现在应该做什么
she understands what is now expected of me.
国王必须要迎娶新妻子
The King must take a new wife.
我永远无法替换你的母亲
I could never replace your mother.
就像我不会让别人替换你成为继承人
No more than I intend to replace you as heir.
但你是我唯一的继承人
But you are my only heir
而我们的血脉太脆弱 太容易被终结了
and our line is vulnerable, too easily ended.
通过再婚
And by marrying again
我可以着手确保更好的防御
I may begin to ensure that we are better defended.
对付谁？
Against whom?
那些胆敢挑战我们的人
Whomever may dare to challenge us.
我不希望我们之间变得疏远
I do not wish to make us estranged.
您是国王
You are the King
所以您的首要责任是国家
and so your first duty is to the realm.
母亲会理解的
Mother would've understood this.
我也是
Just as I do.
早安 大人们
Good morrow, my lords.
我已经决定将迎娶新妻子
I have decided to take a new wife.
我打算娶……
I intend to marry...
阿莉森·海塔尔小姐
the Lady Alicent Hightower
在春天结束前举行婚礼
before spring's end.
太荒谬了
This is an absurdity.
我的家族有瓦雷利亚血脉 有举国最强的力量
My house is Valyrian, the greatest power in the realm.
而我是你的君王
And I am your King.
雷妮拉
Rhaenyra.
瓦列利安家族的起源可以追溯到古瓦雷利亚
House Velaryon's origins reach back to Old Valyria.
甚至比坦格利安家族还古老
More ancient even than House Targaryen
有些记录这么说
according to some texts.
但和坦格利安不同的是
But unlike the Targaryens
我们不是龙王
we were no dragonlords.
几百年来 我们家族不得不
For centuries, my house had to scratch out
依靠勇气和运气
an existence from the sea
在大海中谋生
with grit and luck.
当我坐上浮木王座
When I ascended the Driftwood Throne...
我知道我要的是什么
I knew what I wanted.
所以我走出去攫取
So I went out and seized it.
和这个国家其他领主不同
Unlike every other lord of the realm
我可以说是我自己筑起了家族高位
I can say that I built my house's high seat
凭我自己的实力
with the strength of mine own back.
我一直觉得你和我
I've always thought of you and I
就像一块料子裁出来的
as having been made from the same cloth.
我倒没发现你有个国王老哥
I wasn't aware you had a king for a brother.
我们都是在这个世界上自谋出路的人
We're both men who have had to cut our own way through the world.
我们太常被人忽略了
We've been passed over too often.
你叫我来潮头岛
Did you call me to Driftmark
就为了提醒我的卑微地位吗 科利斯大人
to remind me of my low standing, Lord Corlys
或者还有其他什么原因？
or was there some other reason?
你听说石阶列岛的动乱了吗？
You've heard of the troubles in the Stepstones?
某个密尔亲王用维斯特洛的水手喂螃蟹
Some Myrish prince is feeding Westerosi sailors to the crabs.
我一直在请求国王派我的海军前去那里
I have been petitioning the King to send my navy into the territory
但都被他拒绝了
but he's denied me.
这从来不是我哥哥最擅长的地方
It was never my brother's strongest trait.
什么？
What?
当国王
Being king.
螃蟹喂食者有
The Crabfeeder is backed by
自由贸易城邦内诸多强权的支持
powerful entities within the Free Cities
他们希望削弱维斯特洛
who wish to see Westeros weakened.
而国王的无所作为
And the King's failures
让他积累了实力
have allowed him to accumulate strength.
如果这些航线沦陷……
If those shipping lanes fall...
会让我的家族跛足难行
my house will be crippled.
我不会让潮头岛变成乞丐
And I will not have Driftmark beggared
另一边 我们的国王却在宴会 舞会和比武大会上虚度光阴
while our King idles himself with feasts and balls and tourneys.
我可以肆意评论我哥哥
I will speak of my brother as I wish.
但你不行
You will not.
在石阶列岛等待你的
Waiting in the Stepstones
是一个机会 向那些怀疑你的人
is a chance for you to prove your worth
证明你的价值
to any who might yet doubt it.
我们都是王国的次子 戴蒙
We are the realm's second sons, Daemon.
我们的价值并非别人赠予
Our worth is not given.
而要自己创造
It must be made.